MANOJKUMAR MUNDRA

D-210Ushanagar, Village Road, Bhandup (W), Mumbai-400 078. Mobile: 9969001641 Resi Tel.: 022-25667407

E-mail: camanojmundra1@gmail.com / manojmundra73@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 4th July 1973.



Looking towards a challenging future in a growth oriented & a reputed organization. Support the organization to achieve its goals and objectives.

An Overview

- A dynamic professional with **24+ years** of rich and extensive experience in the categories Accounts, Taxation, Audit and Administration.
- Since July' 18 with Sulzer Pumps India Pvt Ltd as Project Finance controller, called back by the group CFO- Switzerland to join back to support bring in internal management changes.
- Having a rich experience in supervising the finalization of annual accounts, Project Accounting, Project
 Controlling, and annual report of companies with Special emphasis on Accounting Standards and establishing coordination between various source departments and Statutory Auditors.
- Expertise in preparation of Financial Budgets with monthly rollover forecast, Cash Flow, Cash projections, Ratios.
- Skilled & Proficient at finalization of accounts, receivables/ payables management, maintenance of statements & reports. Working knowledge of IFRS. Preparation of CMA reports, Liaison with Banks for Working Capital Requirement and Project Finance. Proficient in Project monitoring and controlling, working out over/under absorption. Preparing KPI's highlighting projects to target. CAPEX management.
- Hands on experience with all financial product categories and resourceful in interfacing with the taxation authorities for filing returns, annual assessment of cases, appeals, refunds for Income-tax.
- Excellent relationship management, analytical and communication skills.

Achievements:

- **Started Project Accounting** (based on Percentage of completion) as per AS-7 in M/s. CMI FPE Ltd. Prepared first Balance Sheet from SAP software and all first internal reporting.
- Awarded Certificate of Achievement in October'2004 by I.M.S. (sister concern of M/s.Pharmapoint (I) Pvt. Ltd.).
- Awarded Best All Rounder of Ratnam College in 1993 94. Topper in College in H.S.C., F.Y.B.Com, S.Y.B.Com and Second in College in T.Y.B.Com.

Professional Experience:

❖ July 2018 till date

Dv. Gen. Manager - Finance in M/s. Sulzer Pumps India Pvt. Ltd, Airoli

- Role since Jan'2020 Project Finance Controller Project Accounting and controlling, MIS reporting, conducting monthly Project review meetings, Monitoring Estimated Costs, variance analysis, Collection Forecast, project close out analysis. Handling Statutory & Internal auditors.
- Order intake and revenue recognition as per IND AS115
- Ensuring timely Milestone collections
- Role since June, 2018 MIS reporting, Monthly closure of books, Finalisation of accounts both statutory and corporate, Budgeting, Direct Taxation, Transfer Pricing, Secretarial compliance, Asset Management, Payables management, Handling statutory and internal auditors.

October 2017 to Jun 2018 [9 months] Chief Finance Officer - Shri Gurudatt Sugars Ltd, Kolhapur

- CMA Data, Interreacting with Bank for enhancement of working capital, Term loan, renewal of Working capital and term loans, bill discounting, etc.
- Budgeting, Forecasting, Capex monitoring. Responsible for finalisation of accounts

....2



September 2012 to July 2016 [3 yrs - 10 months]

Dy. Gen.Manager - Mgnt & Fin. Accounts in M/s.Sulzer Pumps India Ltd, Airoli

- MIS Reporting, Finalisation of Accounts, POC Accounting, etc. for Group companies
- Budgeting, Forecasting, Capex monitoring.
- Handling Direct Taxation, attending assessments, Transfer Pricing, etc.
- Secretarial Compliance in coordination with consultant.
- Handling Internal auditors and Statutory Auditors KPMG, PWC, Sharp & Tannan.

September 2011 to April 2012 [8 months]

General Manager - Finance & Accounts in M/s G.R.Engineering Pvt. Ltd, Worli

- MIS Reporting, Finalisation of Accounts, POC Accounting, etc. for Group companies
- Debtors' management and credit control
- SAP Implementation, Secretarial Compliance.

October 2010 to September 2011 [1 year]

<u>General Manager - Finance & Commercial</u> in M/s JBM MA Automotive Pvt. Ltd. [JBM Group JV with Italian company Magnetto], Chakan, Pune.

- Responsible for Monthly Finalisation of Accounts, MIS reports weekly/monthly basis for Management Committee. Attending statutory auditors.
- Budgeting, Forecasting, Capex monitoring.
- Strengthening of Internal control systems.
- Debtors' management and credit control. Inventory control.
- Liaison with Bank for day to day functioning L/C, Bill discounting, Bank guarantees, etc.
- Responsible for Statutory compliances, taxation (both Direct and Indirect) Tax Audit, VAT Audit.
- Monitoring and managing day to day Cash Flow, Cash Projections weekly, monthly, Annually, Fund Flow.

November 2006 to October 2010 [4 years]

Chief Manager - Accounts in M/s CMI FPE Ltd. [CMI Group, Belgium], Andheri.

- Responsible for Monthly Finalisation of Accounts [**Project Accounting** based on AS-7 Percentage of Completion] and timely reporting to Parent Company with KPI's. Computation of POC. Preparation of various MIS reports and presentations weekly/monthly for MCM and Board Meetings.
- Monitoring & controlling the Project costs, warranty cost, project stock. Track the progress on the projects. Challenging the forecasted cost on the projects in review meetings. Track the billing schedule, collections against the Projects. Monitoring timely closure of the projects and warranty in the SAP system. Reporting non-moving inventories project/plant, Debtors ageing, etc.
- Preparation of Cash Flow Statement, Cash Projections, Fund Flow and various financial ratios and their analysis. Inter company reconciliations.
- Preparation of detailed Business Plans/Budgets with departmental budgets. Preparing rollover forecast each month. Calculating variance of actuals v/s budget with reasons, working out over/under absorption, Order entries and Order book position. Develop/monitor CAPEX budget.
- Supervised T.D.S. compliance, Sales Tax matters, Service Tax, Co-ordinating with Excise Consultant and attending Income Tax Scrutiny hearings, Computation of Income Tax.
- Handling Internal Auditors E&Y and Statutory Auditors Deloitte, Successfully handled auditors from Delloite, PWC and E&Y during due diligence.

.....3

May 2005 to October 2006 [I year 6 months] Sr. Officer - Accounts in M/s Hercules Hoists Ltd. (Bajaj Group), Mulund.

- Accounts Writing & Finalisation of Accounts, T.D.S., Sales Tax return filing to assessment.
- Debtors management, Preparing CMA Reports for working Capital requirement.
- Liaison with bank for working capital requirement & day to day matters.
- Handling Creditors Payments, Cash payments. Tracking advances to staff.

January 2002 to April 2005 [3 years - 4months]

Manager - Finance & Accounts in M/s Pharmapoint (India) Pvt. Ltd., Bandra.

- Handling Accounts Writing & Finalisation of Accounts of the entire group including Direct Tax.
- T.D.S., Sales Tax, Debtors management, Preparing CMA Reports for working Capital requirement.
- Liaison with bank for working capital requirement & day to day matters.
- Office Administration, Placing Orders, attending customer grievances, getting orders, handling Main Cash, Bank Payments, authorizing sales invoices, organizing dispatches, Stock taking, etc.

> June 1999 to May 2001. [2 years]

Asst. Manager (Finance) in M/s Indus Pipeline Co. Pvt. Ltd., Masjid.

- Handling Accounts Writing & Finalisation of Accounts of the entire group.
- Sales Tax matters from Registration to Assessment.
- Computation of Income Tax, Handling T.D.S. matters & Supporting HR for managing Payroll.

July 1997 to May 1999 [1 year 11 months]

Audit Assistant in M/s. A. J. Saboo Associates, Chartered Accountants, Masjid.

- Handling Accounts, Tax Audits & Internal Audits of Companies, Partnership firms and Proprietary concerns of the same Group. Meeting all statutory compliances.
- Income Tax work from computation to Assessment completion of Companies, H.U.F., Partnership firms & Individuals. T.D.S., Preparing CMA Reports for working Capital requirements.

* July 1994 to July 1997 [3 years]

Article Trainee in M/s. M. N. Jhavar & Co. Chartered Accountants, Mulund.

- Handling Statutory Audits of Limited & Private Limited Companies, Banks, etc.
- Accounts writing & finalisation of Accounts (both manual & computerised) of Limited & Private Ltd.
 Cos. & Firms. Income Tax computation of Companies, H.U.F., Partnership firms & Individuals.
- Sales –Tax matters from Registration to Assessments, Appeals of many Private Limited Cos., Partnership firms & Proprietorship Concerns.

Academic Credentials:

Professional

C.A. Final	ICAI	Nov'2006	53%
C.A. Inter	ICAI	May'1997	52%
<u>Educational</u>			
B.Com.	Bombay University	Apr'1994	70%
H.S.C.	Bombay Board	Mar'1991	74%
S.S.C.	Bombay Board	Mar'1989	68%

IT Skills:

Proficient in Ms Excel, Ms Word, Ms Power Point, Tally (Version 7.2) & SAP (version R/3 and ECC6.0).

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY:

ENGLISH, HINDI, MARATHI & MARWARI.

CTC:

Current : ₹37 lacs (excluding benefits) Expected : ₹50 lacs (excluding benefits) **Notice period**: 3 months (negotiable)